# Cougar Rufus Tasker

 ♦ London
 ☑ cougartasker@outlook.com
 • +44 7597 029304
 in cougartasker
 ♠ CougarTasker

## Personal Profile

I am Cougar, a programmer interested in all things computer science, especially computer graphics and machine learning. I have a varied experience of application and full stack development, with a focus on a Typescript/React software stack.

## Skills

Programming Languages: TypeScript, Python, Java, and have worked with many more.

Version Control Systems: Predominantly work with Git and Github, but have used SVN and Gitlab.

API's: Created and used numerous third party RESTful API's.

**Databases:** Created SQL based applications with PostgreSQL and MySql. Familiar with ORM's such as Prisma and Drizzle.

**Deployment:** Deployed Infrastructure as code solutions to Azure, AWS and GCP with Kubernetes and Terraform.

Liunx & Containerisation: I have used many Linux distributions

# Education

# Royal Holloway, University of London

Sept 2019 - July 2024

MSci in Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence

- Final year average >90%, achieved First-Class Honours.
- o Thesis on reinforcement learning: Effective Exploration in Markov Decision Processes
- Developed a robust Java calculator adhering to software engineering principles.
- o Collaborated on a web-based restaurant management system (front-end, back-end, and SQL database).

#### Havant and South Downs College

Sept 2017 - Aug 2019

A-Levels in Computing, Physics, Maths, and Further Maths

- o Achieved grades: AABB
- o Designed a renewable energy-efficient city for the 2050 E4E Challenge, placing third.

# Bourne Community College

Sept 2013 - Aug 2017

- GCSEs
  - Achieved a 9(A\*) in Maths, 5(B) in English, four A's, and two B's.
  - o Completed the Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Award
  - o Helped organise ChiPride event during the National Citizen Service Program.

# Experience

# Software Developer

Paddington, London June 2024 – present

Zing Dev Limited

• Returned as a graduate to continue developing twilio solutions and myself

• Assisted new placements through zing's mentoring programme

# Junior Developer

Paddington, London July 2022 - Aug 2023

Zing Dev Limited

- Year in Industry placement with diverse roles across the software lifecycle.
- Worked collaboratively with customers to implement Twilio solutions.
- o Contributed to design, development, and support tasks.

Paid Internship
Royal Holloway
Aug 2021

• Built a data collection system for BBC iPlayer integration with visualization software.

o Automated site interaction using Selenium and developed a relational PostgreSQL database.

Team Member Chichester

Boston Tea Party

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

• Served tables, ensured customer satisfaction, and managed fast-paced operations.

 ${\bf Steward} \hspace{3cm} Goodwood$ 

Goodwood Festival of Speed

July 2019

 $\circ\,$  Directed and assisted event attendees with professionalism.

Waiter Chichester

Little London Café

Jan 2017 – June 2019

• Progressed responsibilities from dishwashing to payment handling and customer service.

Work Experience Southbourne

Strawberry Soup Nov 2015

o Gained skills in Photoshop, usability testing, and data entry during a sort internship.